GEORGI PETRUSHEV

Owner of L&G

Fort Washington, MD 20744 george.petrushev.bell@gmail.com (443) 824-5866

Highly skilled in Network Engineering and Geographic Information Systems with over 7 years of progressive experience with comprehensive data and telecommunications. Multiskilled professional with good all-round functional and technical expertise. Extensive knowledge of monitoring and controlling data and network communications traffic all while meeting tight deadlines and leadership demands. In 2017 I have started showing interest in programming. Then, I decided to improve my programming skills with different online courses, like TeamTreeHouse, FreeCodeCamp, Udemy. In each course, I developed different sets of technical skills, such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, etc. If you would like to see a more you can check my portfolio(web page) or check my GitHub profile. My current goals as a professional are to learn as much as possible about diverse technologies and to improve my programming skills and knowledge. At this stage of my journey, I would say that I have a good foundation. However, I believe I have a lot to learn. In my opinion, I am a quick learner with a good problem-solving mindset, anything thinking, and I am not afraid to dig deep into more complicated topics.

#readytowork

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Owner

L&G fraight - Fort Washington, MD 2012 to Present

- Deliver goods while operating a tractor-trailer truck, over intercity routes or spanning through several states.
- · Load and unload cargo and record amounts and types of cargo being delivered while taking orders for new deliveries.
- Report to weight services to ensure the execution of following strict state transportation laws, while being in compliance with the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration/DOT rules and regulations, while meeting strict agency and customer delivery deadlines.

GIS Network Analyst

Northstar Solutions Samuel Group (NSSG)

2012 to November 2020

- Help clients enhance their strategic risk awareness in the areas of enterprise risk management, geospatial analytics, crisis management and grants management.
- Facilitate use of technology-based risk assessment tools or methodologies to review, design and implement solutions.
- Identify opportunities for efficiencies in work process and innovative approaches to completing scope of work.
- Participate in team problem solving efforts and offer ideas to solve client issues.
- Conduct relevant research, data analysis, and create reports.

- Maintain responsibility for completion and accuracy of work products.
- Provide technical recommendations for proposal development as requested.
- Actively expand consulting skills and professional development through training courses, mentoring, and daily interaction with clients.

Level III Maintenance Technician

SAMSUNG - Sofia, BG

2009 to 2012

Troubleshot system/network issues and assisted customers with various issues including Microsoft, Novell, PC/Laptop/ Mobile, printer, software, hardware, and network connectivity issues. Provided follow-up support to customers. Served as primary trainer of PC Maintenance Technicians.

- Provided technical expertise to PC Maintenance Techs while assuring prompt and effective response to customer needs and provided timely responses to all service requests. Provided third tier problem analysis.
- Mastered foundational knowledge of assigned applications, hardware and network to support clinical and business environments.
- Independently performed technical downloads and PC configurations. Assisted customers to identify and specify the nature of basic to complex requests or problems.

Hardware/ Software Technician

BULSATCOM - Sofia, BG

2007 to 2009

- Planned installations by reviewing work orders, gathering supplies, evaluating location, locating access, formulating a wiring plan and arranging equipment
- Provided executive level support to consumer when providing, connections, and repairing equipment that delivers television signals to service subscribers.
- · Successfully met high demands when troubleshooting, diagnosing, repairing, replacing and upgrading components
- · Install and program equipment
- Effectively use power tools, hand tools and satellite specific installation tools

Part-time Experience

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

Technical University of Sofia - Sofia, BG 2007 to 2012

Diploma

Technical School of Telecommunication - Sofia, BG 2002 to 2007

COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSE (CDL)

Class A

Expires: March 2020

State: MD

SKILLS

- · CCNA (5 years)
- JavaScript (2 years)
- HTML5 (2 years)
- C++ (Less than 1 year)
- C (Less than 1 year)
- CSS (2 years)
- Node.js
- React
- LAN
- JQuery
- Fetch API

LINKS

https://georgipetrushev.github.io/portfolio-master/

https://github.com/GeorgiPetrushev?tab=repositories

https://www.facebook.com/georgi.petrushev/

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Analytical Skills: Analyze complex network systems to find flaws or to make improvements.
- Produce complex blueprints for communication networks and ensure systems continuity of operations in emergency situations.
- Ability to create accurate network diagrams and documentation for design and planning of network systems.
- Constantly maintain and improve network security by establishing firewalls to ensure only authorized entry.
- Highly skilled and knowledgeable in the understanding of network infrastructure and network hardware.
- Ability to implement, administer, and troubleshoot network infrastructure devices, including: wireless access points, firewall, routers, switches, controllers, etc.